Records of the U.S. District Court for the District of Columbia; Law, Appellate, and Criminal Records; Case Papers 1802-1863
Center for Digital Research in the Humanities University of Nebraska–Lincoln
- Records of the U.S. District Court for the District of Columbia; Law, Appellate, and Criminal Records; Case Papers 1802-1863
  - Civil Trials, 1-170, Robert Barry v. Martha Rice; 1825, December; hire of slaves to work in tanyard $806.00 (Box 358, Folder 122)
  - Civil Trials, 1-170, Martha Diggs v. John D. Freeman; 1825, December; "Board of negro Bill 6 weeks when sick" 15.00 (Box 358, Folder 144)
  - Civil Trials, 175-379, 1825, December (Box 359)
  - Civil Trials, 381-466, 1825, December (Box 360)
  - Civil Trials, 470-575, 1825, December (Box 361)
  - Civil Trials, 577-684, 1825, December (Box 362)
  - Civil Trials, 1-138, 1825, December (Box 363)
  - Civil Trials, 172-335, 1825, December (Box 364)
  - Civil Trials, 337-447, Imparlances, Rough Bundle, Titlings for Executions, Titlings for Writs, Samuel Redmon v. Philip Mauro; 1825, December; the property seized consisted of "one negro Woman named Rosetta and her two children one named Deloze [?] about ﬁfteen years of age and the other named Matrice about 12 years of age," together worth $697.00, and "one Piano Forte," worth $150.00 (Box 365, Folder 40)
  - Civil Trials, 337-447, Imparlances, Rough Bundle, Titlings for Executions, Titlings for Writs, Union Bank v. Jesse Scott; 1825, December; property seized was "one negro Woman named Fanny about seventeen years of age," worth $300.00; in the previous case (134), same litigants, property seized included "one mahogany secretary and bookcase, one mahogany sofa covered with hair cloth, one dozen rush bottomed chairs, one pair handsome guilt [sic] looking glasses." (Box 365, Folder 135)
  - Civil Trials, 337-447, Imparlances, Rough Bundle, Titlings for Executions, Titlings for Writs, Thomas Ewell v. Joseph Gates; 1825, December; property seized included three slaves, Eliza, Susan and Abraham, with a total value of $650.00 (total value of property was $2190.00) (Box 365, Folder 278)
  - Civil Trials, 337-447, Imparlances, Rough Bundle, Titlings for Executions, Titlings for Writs, Union Bank v. James Moore; 1825, December; "one negro girl named Ann about ten years of age," worth $200.00 (Box 365, Folder 326)
  - Civil Trials, 337-447, Imparlances, Rough Bundle, Titlings for Executions, Titlings for Writs, 1825, December; Apprenticeship ﬁle William Hawley’s petition to be relieved of "John Bush a free coloured boy" indentured as a house servant, "who has turned out to be idle & mischievous.... Petitioner has tried such means of correction & reformation, as to satisfy him, that not only his own ease & the good order of his family will be much disturbed by the continuance of said Boy in his service..., but that the morals & habits of the Boy will become so lax & deranged, as probably to produce depravity of character in him & injurious consequences to society.... [I]f the said Indentures be discharged & the Boy bound again to some steady & industrious mechanic, he may still acquire habits of industry & good conduct, that will redeem him from the destruction that threatens." (Box 365, Folder rough bundle)
  - May, Civil Appearances, 1-150, Negro George v. Gabriel Adams; 1826,; petition for freedom (Box 366, Folder 13)
  - May, Civil Appearances, 1-150, George Hunter v. W.M. & Z. Offutt; 1826,; petition for freedom (Box 366, Folder 63)
  - May, Civil Appearances, 1-150, Milly Bowie v. W.M. & Z. Offutt; 1826,; petition for freedom (Box 366, Folder 64)
  - May, Civil Appearances, 153-412, 1826 (Box 367)
  - May, Civil Trials, 1-198, Prince Gray v. Joel T. Gustine; 1826,; petition for freedom (Box 368, Folder 44)
  - May, Civil Trials, 200-350, David Africana v. John Strother; 1826,; petition for freedom (Box 369, Folder 309)
  - May, Civil Trials, 200-350, Sally Baker & children v. Hay & Cayce; 1826,; petition for freedom (Box 369, Folder 310)
  - May, Civil Trials, 354-437, 1826 (Box 370)
  - May, Civil Trials, 440-511, Recognizances, Rough Bundle, Letty Brown & child v. John H. Lowe; 1826,; petition for freedom (Box 371, Folder 508)
  - May, Civil Trials, 440-511, Recognizances, Rough Bundle, Negro William v. George Milburn et al.; 1826,; petition for freedom (Box 371)
  - May, Civil Trials, 440-511, Recognizances, Rough Bundle, U.S. v. Negro Bob alias Robert Johnson James Pumphrey and John Wheat; 1826,; furnished Johnson’s bond in the amount of $25 each on a charge of theft (Box 371, Folder unnumbered)
  - May, Appeals, Criminal Appearances and Trials, U.S. v. Abraham Williams; 1826,; "negro Abraham Williams...did aid and assist one negress Mary the slave of one William L. Brent, in her endeavors to escape from the service of her master..." (Box 372, Folder 19)
  - May, Appeals, Criminal Appearances and Trials, U.S. v. William Hanson; 1826,; "a negro Boy 12 years of age for theft, in stealing one silver watch, some ear rings, &c of the value of Five dollars..." (Box 372, Folder 26)
  - May, Appeals, Criminal Appearances and Trials, U.S. v. Henny & Anna Gray; 1826,; keeping a disorderly house (Box 372, Folder 39)
  - May, Appeals, Criminal Appearances and Trials, U.S. v. John Gusty; 1826,; assault and battery (Box 372, Folder 40)
  - May, Appeals, Criminal Appearances and Trials, U.S. v. Henry Dant; 1826,; stealing four pieces of copper worth $2.00 (Box 372, Folder 42)
  - May, Appeals, Criminal Appearances and Trials, US. v. Betsey Payne; 1826,; stealing clothing and money worth $2.75 (Box 372, Folder 43)
  - May, Appeals, Criminal Appearances and Trials, U.S. v. Elijah Shay; 1826,; "for having forged a pass for a negro Man, named John the property of Majr Geo Peter..." (Box 372, Folder 56)
  - May, Appeals, Criminal Appearances and Trials, U.S. v. Betsey Palmer; 1826,; stealing clothing worth $13.50 (Box 372, Folder 72)
  - May, Appeals, Criminal Appearances and Trials, U.S. v. Eleanor Wilson; 1826,; stealing clothing worth $2.25 (Box 372, Folder 73)
  - May, Appeals, Criminal Appearances and Trials, U.S. v. Robert Butler; 1826,; stealing clothing worth $4.00 (Box 372, Folder 90)
  - May, Imparlances, Judicials, 1-54, 1826 (Box 373)
  - May, Judicials, 212-422, Titlings for Executions, Titlings for Writs, U.S. v. Negro Mary Bruce; 1826,; pardoned by the President (Box 374, Folder 233)
  - May, Judicials, 212-422, Titlings for Executions, Titlings for Writs, E. Smallwood v. J. H. Wilson; 1826,; "one Negro boy...aged about 13 years" $200.00 (Box 374, Folder 378)
  - Civil Appearances, 6-155, Negro William v. —— Alford; 1826, December; petition for freedom (Box 375, Folder 18)
  - Civil Appearances, 6-155, Negro George v. Gabrield Adams; 1826, December; petition for freedom; Black Washingtonians says "Gabrield" (Box 375, Folder 89)
  - Civil Appearances, 6-155, Nace Humphreys v. John B. Lambert; 1826, December; petition for freedom (Box 375, Folder 90)
  - Civil Appearances, 6-155, J. Johnson & W. Booth v. G. Booth; 1826, December; "negro man Joe aged about 26 years" $350.00 (Box 375, Folder 145)
  - Civil Appearances, 157-375, Lizett Lee v. Augustus Preuss; 1826, December; petition for freedom (Box 376, Folder 256)
  - Civil Appearances, 378-638, Janette Lee v. Augustus Preuss; 1826, December; petition for freedom (Box 377, Folder 389)
  - Civil Appearances, 378-638, Nancy Lee v. Augustus Preuss; 1826, December; petition for freedom (Box 377, Folder 390)
  - Civil Trials, 2-225, Prince Gray v. Catharine Linn; 1826, December; petition for freedom (Box 378)
  - Civil Trials, 2-225, Travers Dixon v. William Herbert; 1826, December; petition for freedom (Box 378)
  - Civil Trials, 2-225, James Shields v. Mary Semmes; 1826, December; hire of slaves $ 579.73 3/4 (Box 378)
  - Civil Trials, 231-364, 1826, December (Box 379)
  - Civil Trials, 367-458, 1826, December (Box 380)
  - Civil Trials, 465-575, 1826, December (Box 381)
  - Appeals, Criminal Appearances, Criminal Trials, U.S. v. Negress Louisa Reed; 1826, December; Riot, and pulling down a house worth $5.00 (Box 382, Folder 45)
  - Appeals, Criminal Appearances, Criminal Trials, U.S. v. Negress Louisa Reed; 1826, December; Stealing a piece of scantling worth 50 cents (Box 382, Folder 46)
  - Appeals, Criminal Appearances, Criminal Trials, U.S. v. Negress Mary Jasper; 1826, December; Stealing a shawl worth $1.00 (Box 382, Folder 56)
  - Appeals, Criminal Appearances, Criminal Trials, U.S. v. Negro George Allen; 1826, December; Assault and battery (ﬁne $20.00) (Box 382, Folder 72)
  - Imparlances, Judicials, 1-239, Bank of the United States v. John Threlkeld; 1826, December; Contains the most complete account of a slave sale yet; includes both estimates (with ages), and the actual price of sale (Box 383, Folder 4)
  - Imparlances, Judicials, 1-239, R. & W.A. Smallwood v. John Carlon et al. "; 1826, December; One negro boy named Dennis Shaw aged about 12 years" $300.00 (Box 383, Folder 124)
  - Imparlances, Judicials, 1-239, J.A. & O. Wilson v. W. Dement; 1826, December; "one black man named Bazil aged about 25 years" $350.00 (Box 383, Folder 229)
  - Judicials, 241-367, Recognizances, Titlings for Executions & Writs, 1826, December (Box 384)
  - May, Civil Appearances, 8-239, Negro David v. James Hutchison; 1827,; petition for freedom; Black Washingtonians says "Hutchinson" (Box 385, Folder 48)
  - May, Civil Appearances, 8-239, John Baptist Lee v. Augustus Preuss; 1827,; petition for freedom (Box 385, Folder 62)
  - May, Civil Appearances, 8-239, Negro George v. Gabriel Adams; 1827,; petition for freedom (Box 385, Folder 70)
  - May, Civil Appearances, 8-239, Lizette Lee v. Augustus Preuss; 1827,; petition for freedom (Box 385, Folder 109)
  - May, Civil Appearances, 8-239, Janette Lee v. Augustus Preuss; 1827,; petition for freedom (Box 385, Folder 110)
  - May, Civil Appearances, 8-239, Nancy Lee v. Augustus Preuss; 1827,; petition for freedom (Box 385, Folder 111)
  - May, Civil Appearances, 242-458, Criminal Appearances, Negro Betsey v. George McCandless; 1827,; petition for freedom (Box 386, Folder 258)
  - May, Civil Appearances, 242-458, Criminal Appearances, Sylvia Lee v. Elizabeth Smallwood; 1827,; petition for freedom (Box 386, Folder 282)
  - May, Civil Appearances, 242-458, Criminal Appearances, U.S. v. Negro Alfred William; 1827,; assault & battery (Box 386, Folder 14)
  - May, Civil Appearances, 242-458, Criminal Appearances, U.S. v. Negress Polly Mason; 1827,; stealing an axe and an iron pot worth $1.50 (Box 386, Folder 16)
  - May, Civil Appearances, 242-458, Criminal Appearances, U.S. v. Negro Andrew; 1827,; stealing items worth $5.00 (Box 386, Folder 24)
  - May, Civil Appearances, 242-458, Criminal Appearances, U.S. v. Negro Jerry Norris; 1827,; attempted arson (Box 386, Folder 29)
  - May, Civil Appearances, 242-458, Criminal Appearances, U.S. v. Negro William Chubb; 1827,; stealing a pair of boots worth $2.00 (Box 386, Folder 35)
  - May, Civil Appearances, 242-458, Criminal Appearances, U.S. v. Negro Nace Lee; 1827,; stealing a spade worth $1.00 (Box 386, Folder 48)
  - May, Civil Appearances, 242-458, Criminal Appearances, U.S. v. Negress Eliza Grandison; 1827,; stealing two gowns worth $2.00 (Box 386, Folder 65)
  - May, Civil Appearances, 242-458, Criminal Appearances, U.S. v. Negro Harry Collins; 1827,; stealing items worth 70 cents (Box 386, Folder 72)
  - May, Civil Trials, 23-222, Negroes Frank & Maria Jennifer v. Thomas Ewell; 1827,; petition for freedom (Box 387, Folder 200)
  - May, Civil Trials, 224-341, 1827 (Box 388)
  - May, Civil Trials, 344-443, 1827 (Box 389)
  - May, Judicials, 4-212, John Fleming v. J.P. Vanness et al.; 1827,; Lists $4000 property, $2000 of it in slaves (Box 390, Folder 44)
  - May, Judicials, 4-212, Richard Wallach v. Lewin Talbot; 1827,; negro woman Mary aged 34 years $250.00 negro boy Harry aged 10 years 150.00 negro girl Ellen aged 11 years 100.00 (Box 390, Folder 135)
  - May, Judicials, 4-212, Richard Wallach v. Henry Talbott; 1827,; Charles, 10, $150; Henry, 8, $100; Emma, 6, $100; Charity, 6, $100; Frank, 4, $100; Polly, 25, with Thomas, 16 months, $300 (Box 390, Folder 136)
  - May, Judicials, 214-369, 1827 (Box 391)
  - May, Appeals, Criminal Trials, Imparlances, Recognizances, Rough Bundle, Titlings for Executions & Writs, 1827; "Habeas Corpus" ﬁle Negro George (George Chambers) claimed to be held against his will on the schooner Agate, "now lying in the eastern branch of the Potomac within the jurisdiction of this court..." (Box 392, Folder rough bundle)
  - Civil Appearances, 1-204, Richard Hall v. Abraham Vanmetre; 1827, December; petition for freedom (Box 393, Folder 13)
  - Civil Appearances, 208-438, Criminal Appearances, U.S. v. Negro Elie Davis; 1827, December; assault and battery (Box 394, Folder 34)
  - Civil Appearances, 208-438, Criminal Appearances, U.S. v. Negro William Chubb; 1827, December; stealing clothing worth $5, "and six silver half dollars of the value of three dollars" (Box 394, Folder 35)
  - Civil Appearances, 208-438, Criminal Appearances, U.S. v. Negro Nancy Reed; 1827, December; stealing china and glassware worth $15.00 (Box 394, Folder 38)
  - Civil Appearances, 208-438, Criminal Appearances, US. v. Negro Henry Simms; 1827, December; stealing one pair of shoes worth $1.50 (Box 394, Folder 41)
  - Civil Appearances, 208-438, Criminal Appearances, US. v. Negro James Young; 1827, December; stealing one pair of boots worth $3.00 (Box 394, Folder 69)
  - Civil Appearances, 208-438, Criminal Appearances, U.S. v. Negro Emily Starris; 1827, December; stealing one quilt ($1) and three pairs of shoes ($4) (Box 394, Folder 72)
  - Civil Trial, 9-212, James D. Barry v. Robert Barry; 1827, December; part of this extraordinarily long case, contained in the second of three folders, involves a "negro woman Anna a slave for life," who was taken "out of the District of Columbia to some one of the northern cities" (Box 395, Folder 115)
  - Civil Trials, 251-370, 1827, December (Box 396)
  - Civil Trials, 372-521, Thomas L. Mitchell v. William Wilson; 1827, December; "one negro girl named Mahala about 21 years of age" $250.00 (Box 397, Folder 508)
  - Appeals, Imparlances, Recognizances, Rough Bundle, Titlings for Executions & Writs, 1827, December; "John Walker & Rachel Walker free persons of colour" post $100 bond each "in case the said John Walker shall not...give evidence...against a certain Eli Davis also a free person of colour...for stabbing & wounding him the said Jno Walker with a knife In several places on his body on the 10th June 1827...." (Box 398, Folder (August folder))
  - Appeals, Imparlances, Recognizances, Rough Bundle, Titlings for Executions & Writs, 1827, December; Habeas corpus of "Robert Bell, a free Man of colour"—the case involves custody of a child (Box 398, Folder rough bundle)
  - Judicials, 1-189, 1827, December (Box 399, Folder 15)
  - Judicials, 191-296, W. Smith v. Z. Hazle & J. Thomas; 1827, December; "one negro boy named George aged about 16 years more or less" appraised at $175; sold for $143 (Box 400)
  - May, Civil Appearances, 2-353, Louisa Johnson v. Milo Mason; 1828,; petition for freedom (Box 401, Folder 30)
  - May, Civil Appearances, 2-353, Abraham Smith v. John Lyons; 1828,; petition for freedom (Box 401, Folder 353)
  - May, Civil Appearances, 367-432, Criminal Appearances, Robert Loyal v. Benjamin Lewis; 1828,; petition for freedom (Box 402, Folder 408)
  - May, Civil Appearances, 367-432, Criminal Appearances, U.S. v. Scipio Brown; 1828,; About this time, the clerk began to give up specifying black defendants by race in the docket books and printed forms, but "negro" and "negress" continue to appear in small, hand-written notes in most ﬁles.; assault and battery on "negro Thomas Green" (Box 402, Folder 43)
  - May, Civil Appearances, 367-432, Criminal Appearances, U.S. v. Thomas D. Thomas; 1828,; perjury; Thomas, a white man, swore to the truth of a false bill for services presented by "negro William Barton" (Box 402, Folder 45)
  - May, Civil Appearances, 367-432, Criminal Appearances, U.S. v. William Barton; 1828,; presenting a false bill for services amounting to $157.50 (Box 402, Folder 46)
  - May, Civil Appearances, 367-432, Criminal Appearances, U.S. v. Maria Jones; 1828,; stealing "sundry articles of cloathing" worth $5.00 (Box 402, Folder 48)
  - May, Civil Appearances, 367-432, Criminal Appearances, US. v. Phyllis Butler; 1828,; stealing "one piece of silver money the amount not known" (Box 402, Folder 49)
  - May, Civil Appearances, 367-432, Criminal Appearances, U.S. v. Maria Jones; 1828,; stealing "one silver spoon" worth $1.50 (Box 402, Folder 50)
  - May, Civil Appearances, 367-432, Criminal Appearances, U.S. v. Henry Sims; 1828,; stealing "silver and copper money" amounting to $2.00 (Box 402, Folder 51)
  - May, Civil Appearances, 367-432, Criminal Appearances, U.S. v. Frank Hanson; 1828,; stealing money and one pair of shoes, worth $15.62 1/2 (Box 402, Folder 52)
  - May, Civil Appearances, 367-432, Criminal Appearances, U.S. v. Isreal Chubb; 1828,; ("a person of evil name and fame, and of dishonest conversation, and a common buyer and receiver of stolen goods") accepted and held ﬁve dollars of Hanson’s stolen money (Box 402, Folder 53)
  - May, Civil Trials, 1-172, John Battaile v. Thomas Miller; 1828,; petition for freedom; Black Washingtonians says "Battle" (Box 403, Folder 135)
  - May, Civil Trials, 174-328, 1828 (Box 404)
  - May, Civil Trials, 330-437, Negro James v. Ignatius Newton; 1828,; indentured; Black Washingtonians says petition for freedom (Box 405, Folder 425)
  - May, Appeals, Criminal Trials, Imparlances, Recognizances, Titlings for Executions & Writs, U.S. v. Negress Margaret Holland; 1828,; stealing 3 decanters and 7 wine glasses worth $10.00 (Box 406, Folder 4)
  - May, Appeals, Criminal Trials, Imparlances, Recognizances, Titlings for Executions & Writs, U.S. v. Negress Louisa Holland; 1828,; same case (Box 406, Folder 5)
  - May, Appeals, Criminal Trials, Imparlances, Recognizances, Titlings for Executions & Writs, US. V. Negro John Marlbro; 1828,; receiving stolen bank notes worth $5.00 (Box 406, Folder 7)
  - May, Judicials, 1-169, 1828 (Box 407)
  - May, Judicials, 172-244, 1828 (Box 408)
  - Civil Appearances, 1-246, Christopher Harris v. Penelope B. Alexander; 1828, December; petition for freedom (Box 409, Folder 16)
  - Civil Appearances, 1-246, Henry Ober et al. v. Henry Talbert; 1828, December; petition for freedom (Box 409, Folder 21)
  - Civil Appearances, 1-246, D. & L.L. Butler v. J.H. Beall; 1828, December; "one negro woman named Harriott aged about 24 years and her child named Fanny aged about 4 years," appraised at $300.00 (Box 409, Folder 33)
  - Civil Appearances, 1-246, J.S. Clarke & W.C. Orme v. D. Magruder; 1828, December; "one negro man said to be about 60 years old named Nat," appraised at $50.00; "one negro boy named Washington aged about 11 years," appraised at $100.00 (Box 409, Folder 40, 41)
  - Civil Appearances, 1-246, Negro George v. Gabriel Adams; 1828, December; petition for freedom (Box 409, Folder 62)
  - Civil Appearances, 1-246, Rebecca Rawlings v. W. Wallace & J. Dallerhite; 1828, December; petition for freedom; Black Washingtonians says "Dallerhide" (Box 409, Folder 161)
  - Civil Appearances, 257-452, Criminal Appearances, U.S. v. Negress Betsey Ware; 1828, December; stealing "one Cambiick frock" worth $10.00 (Box 410, Folder 3)
  - Civil Appearances, 257-452, Criminal Appearances, US. v. John Young; 1828, December; stabbing "negro Cornelius Butler" (Box 410, Folder 5)
  - Civil Appearances, 257-452, Criminal Appearances, U.S. v. Negro Philip Sims; 1828, December; stealing 1 pair shoes worth $2.25 (Box 410, Folder 27)
  - Civil Appearances, 257-452, Criminal Appearances, U.S. v. Negro William Chubb; 1828, December; stealing silverware worth $1.50 (Box 410, Folder 29)
  - Civil Appearances, 257-452, Criminal Appearances, U.S. v. Daniel Huntt; 1828, December; stealing 2 pair of shoes worth $9.00 (Box 410, Folder 33)
  - Civil Appearances, 257-452, Criminal Appearances, U.S. v. William Chubb; 1828, December; broke and entered and stole $1.25 in silver money (Box 410, Folder 34)
  - Civil Appearances, 257-452, Criminal Appearances, U.S. v. Negro Peter Dulany; 1828, December; stealing a saddle worth $10.00 (Box 410, Folder 35)
  - Civil Appearances, 257-452, Criminal Appearances, U.S. v. Negro Peter Dulany; 1828, December; stealing a horse worth $75 and a saddle worth $500 (Box 410, Folder 36)
  - Civil Appearances, 257-452, Criminal Appearances, U.S. v. Negress Mary Thompson; 1828, December; stealing "sundry articles of clothing" worth $15.00 (Box 410, Folder 37)
  - Civil Appearances, 257-452, Criminal Appearances, U.S. v. Negro Robert Barnes; 1828, December; stealing silver and copper money worth $2.00 (Box 410, Folder 39)
  - Civil Appearances, 257-452, Criminal Appearances, US. v. Negro Henry Butler; 1828, December; stealing a hat worth $5.00 (Box 410, Folder 54)
  - Civil Appearances, 257-452, Criminal Appearances, U.S. V. Negro Henry Butler; 1828, December; stealing a hat worth $2.00 (Box 410, Folder 75)
  - Civil Appearances, 257-452, Criminal Appearances, U.S. v. Negro Reuben Duskins; 1828, December; stealing bedclothes and tableware worth $2.50 (Box 410, Folder 81)
  - Civil Appearances, 257-452, Criminal Appearances, U.S. v. Nelson Sims; 1828, December; stealing goods and money worth $5.85 (Box 410, Folder 103)
  - Civil Appearances, 257-452, Criminal Appearances, U.S. v Negro George Hanson; 1828, December; stealing a joist worth $1.00 (Box 410, Folder 104)
  - Civil Trials, 5-176, Mandeville & Larrnour v. Cookendorfer; 1828, December; "A List of.. .Expences to Boston in pursuit of slave Richard Bunbury" $189.37 (Box 411, Folder 105)
  - Civil Trials, 5-176, Mason & Moore v. Matilda Derrick and children; 1828, December; petition for freedom (Box 411, Folder 113)
  - Civil Trials, 5-176, Negro Ben v. James Moore; 1828, December; petition for freedom (Box 411, Folder 115)
  - Civil Trials, 179-277, 1828, December (Box 412)
  - Civil Trials, 281-369, 1828, December (Box 413)
  - Civil Trials, 370-440, Appeals, Phyllis Clagett and children v. Ann Gibson; 1828, December; petition for freedom (Box 414, Folder 402)
  - Civil Trials, 370-440, Appeals, Abraham Smith v. John Lyon; 1828, December; petition for freedom (Box 414, Folder 417)
  - Criminal Trials, Imparlances, Recognizances, Rough Bundle, Titlings for Executions & Writs, U.S. v. George Graham; 1828, December; "for kidnapping a negro boy named James Cudgel" (Box 415, Folder 7)
  - Judicials, 1-140, Thomas F. Anderson v. James Moore; 1828, December; "one negro man named Torn aged about 38 years of a dark complexion" $400.00 (Box 416, Folder 57)
  - Judicials, 157-232, 1828, December (Box 417)
  - May, Civil Appearances, 1-275, Harry Wigle et al. v. George Kirby; 1829,; petition for freedom (Box 418, Folder 26)
  - May, Civil Appearances, 1-275, John Lee v. William Dent; 1829,; petition for freedom (Box 418, Folder 83)
  - May, Civil Appearances, 1-275, Negro Ann Williams and children v. George Miller; 1829,; petition for freedom; Black Washingtonians says "Williamson" (Box 418, Folder 97)
  - May, Civil Appearances, 1-275, William P. Compton v. George Milburn; 1829,; "one negro boy named Merrick aged about 13 years" $250.00 (Box 418, Folder 119)
  - May, Civil Appearances, 284-396, Imparlances, 1829 (Box 419)
  - May, Criminal Appearances, U.S. v. Negro Jesse Lane; 1829,; stealing four walking canes worth $8.00 (Box 420, Folder 50)
  - May, Criminal Appearances, U.S. v. Negro Cupid (Edgar Cupid alias Spencer Day); 1829,; stealing three silver tablespoons and three plated "Desart" spoons worth $7.00 (Box 420, Folder 51)